# Sittukala Saravanan +44-7934438559

sittukalas@gmail.com

ssa46@student.le.ac.uk

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sittukala-saravanan-30b890a3

#### Leicester-LE1 6UP

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

A meticulous and enthusiastic Developer having a great passion towards full stack development with 3+ years of experience in Infosys Limited and with innovative ideas and spontaneous approaches to quickly solve a problem situation or come up with a workaround which highly saved time and effort in my previous experience. I am a quick learner with a scrutinized observation and self-scheduled attitude that keeps me on track.

I am currently pursuing my Masters in Advanced Computer Science in University of Leicester. I am seeking a competitive and challenging environment where I can serve your organization and explore more in my career.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Backend Programming Languages	
Preferred Language	JAVA
Backend Framework	Springboot
Other Languages	C#, C++, Python
Database Support Languages	
RDBMS	MSSQL, MySQL
Cluster based DB	NoSQL, MongoDB
Browser Based Technologies	
Rendering Engine Support	HTML, CSS
Dynamic JS Engine	Javascript
Responsive Web Design	Bootstrap
Front-end Framework	ReactJS, Angular 9
Siemens PLM Technologies	
Rich client (RAC)	Teamcenter
Thin client	Active Workspace Configuration

## **EDUCATION**

University of Leicester

MSc in Advanced Computer Science

Leicester

Sept 2019 - May 2020

• **Coursework:** Internet and Cloud Computing Advanced Web Technologies, Software Measurement and Quality Assurance, Agile Cloud Automation.

**R.M.K Engineering College** 

**B.E Computer Science Engineering** 

Chennai

Aug 2012 - May 2016

• **Coursework:** SQL, Java, C/C++, Web Technologies, Design and Analysis of Algorithm, System Design, Software Architecture, Computer Networks, Object Oriented Programming, Unified Modelling Language.

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE:

# Product Development Summer Intern(Remote) Uniglows

Chennai June 2020 – Aug 2020

- Currently working as Product Development intern with Uniglows. Started as a volunteer and now working with them as a part of summer internship.
- Initially started with product-based research and gathering requirements directly from end-users and conducting surveys with stakeholders.
- I am currently working on front-end part with Angular 9, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap to get the better responsive web application for the end-users.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Limited

Chennai Aug 2016 – Sept 2019

- Worked as Senior Systems Engineer in Product Lifecycle Management domain at Infosys Limited, Chennai for the past 3 years gaining enough knowledge in various Teamcenter applications.
- Experience in ITK customization and more experience in all areas of AWC Configuration. Sole responsibility for the complete configuration perspectives in the project and customizations mostly using C or Java.
- Experience in Teamcenter Patching, AWC Patching process. Additionally, explored more on Teamcenter and Active workspace Application Installation, Cloning Environment, BMIDE customizations, OTW(Over The Web) and deployment.

#### **INTERNSHIP**

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Limited Chennai

Feb 2016 - Aug 2016

Done internship at Infosys Campus, Mysore during college final year.

## **Internship Trainings**

- Trained in several programming languages like Python, Java and C++.
- Monitored performance with multiple levels of testing systems.
- Trained in Teamcenter platform under PLM domain

#### Internship Project

- Presented a Teamcenter Project titled 'Managing Structures and Parts of a Global Vehicle Sector' Live Demo at Infosys.
- This project deals with creating various parts with specific requirements and synchronizing the flow of tasks with multiple workflows and approval at various levels of signoff team for the products about to deliver at the delivery unit.

### **QUALIFICATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Certified from Cambridge ESOL Examinations in Business English Certificate Vantage Council of Europe Level B2.
- Scored 8.78 CGPA in B.E securing **37th rank** under Anna University.

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Quick Learner: I am quick learner which I proved in my previous employment. I worked in a 4-member team where each person is solely responsible for their modules. When a situation came where one must quit suddenly, I was able to take over his module with a fast-paced KT session over two weeks of time which was quite challenging.
- **Communication**: I have good communication skills. I had the chances to work closely with clients in calls and discussions as an in-charge of Developer team in my project at Infosys.

REFERENCE: Available on request.